CAREER SUMMARY

Over 6 years in customer service fields and 9 years in Billing and Account Receivable function. Excellent communicator with good time management and problem-solving skills. Solid experience in shared service industry being the expert in billing operation & account receivable of the Asia Pacific and Middle East and Africa (AMEA) region. Experience in transition project with different billing knowledge, credit control process, escalation management and audit field work. Interact with multiple stakeholders like Finance team, Tax Team, Sales, IT team, Operation Team and Network Operation Team. Lead in ERP Billing System migration project.

SKILLS INVENTORY

•	Green Belt Six Sigma	•	Oracle system	•	Real Estate System
•	ARIBA/Tungsten/Cuopa	•	Problem Solving	•	People Management
•	Project Transition	•	BOSS	•	Negotiation

CAREER EXPERIENCE

Sept 2022- Present

Account Receivable and Credit Control

Account Receivable and Credit Control is responsible for billing or issuing invoices, allocation payment (cash application), and credit control on aging. Managing disputes with external & internal stakeholders and managing audits.

- Support the Accounts Receivable accounting team and partner with the AR Team Leader to provide accurate books and records and comply with global processes/standards
- Accountable for all customer disputes and owning these through to resolution
- Responsible and advised end customers on (receivables) accounting issues. Maintain, consult, and adhere to (local) AR policies.
- Engaged with the leasing team on collection exercise status and unapplied payment
- Provide guidance and expertise in the accounts receivable area to improve revenue and credit control
- Managing month-end reporting required by a different stakeholder from an AR perspective.
- Appointed as project manager of IRBM E-invoicing project and target live in June 2024.

May 2021- Aug 2022

Credit Controller: Assistant Manager (AM)

Credit Controller responsible for assessing credit applications and adhering to company payment policies includes managing escalation on the payment issue or billing dispute with coordinate with marketing sales and Network team. Delegate tasks by managing revenue activity (Billing) and payment activity (Cash application).

- Collaborated and successfully identified improvement process in cash application activity by creating reconciliation reports resulting in reduced error less 1% per month.
- Deliver month-end post activity by preparing reports required by upper management with ageing debt collection, collection movement and balance sheet report within SLA.
- Responsible for managing portfolio of accounts; utilizing phone calls, emails, and interpersonal communications to ensure that Accounts Receivable are collected in accordance with company policy resulting in a reduction of 30% aging.
- Responsible for regular review on >60days debts to ensure an action plan to resolve is in place and follow-up closely.
- Collaborate with respective stakeholders to resolve dispute items and improve dispute resolution turnaround time
- Accomplished on payment schedule requested by the customer to reduce the ageing amount resulting10% collection record.

Technology (M) Sdn Bhd August 2018- Mar 2021 AMEA International Billing/AR : Subject Matter Expert (SME)

Subject Matter Expert (SME) responsible for all escalation and inquiry from differentstakeholders is the lead of billing operation wise. Delegate task among the team member to ensureall the task completed within the time given and effectively. Acting as Audit Quality Checking, AMEARegion Account Receivable, Vendor Invoice Billing & Payment and PO by working with the Account Payable (AP) team and supporting Billing System Migration (ERP development).

- Responsible by being 1st point of contact by managing 7 people of team member which is 5 people in MEA Region (23 country), 2 people in SEA region which is 1 person in Singapore country and 1 person for Sri Lanka and Bangladesh with revenue over GBP 15,000,000 million/month.
- Managed Project Transition for APAC billing (Sri Lanka, Bangladesh & Singapore) and successfully completed within 1 month with develop SOP.
- Successfully coach and mentor newbies with no experience to be able to work with minimum supervise within 2 months.
- Responsible with month-end activity with preparing reporting to upper management with unbilled accrual report, credit note report, reason of missed billing with the analyst detail and action plan.
- Responsible for process of improvement/excellence for the team, drive and completed3 Project (Lean Six Sigma) which is contributed to 4 hrs/month of saving.
- Provide guidance and expertise in the account receivable arena within contract team, billing team and finance by reducing 98% of incorrect revenue bookings including reclassifications and manual amortizations.
- AR end to end journey including Uploading customer's invoices/AR to Global Finance Platform (GFP) portals to prepare daily, weekly, and monthly reconciliation files for revenue bookings.
- Collaborated with collection with updating aging debt report and chasing customer payment

- by archive collection target 90%
- Collaborated in the Migration system from legally system (pastel billing system) to BOSS billing system (new system) with the development team, technical team and AMEA billing lead (project manager) by evaluating the system (UAT) before going live being used in the AMEA region (49 country).
- The 2019 Best Subject Matter Expert Award contributed to the new idea of using the billing team to manage escalation with minimum supervision and 4 abilities in the billing system.

December 2014 - July 2018

International Billing Analyst - Operation

Managed all Middle East & African (MEA) region on Telecom Billing service, disengagement of the Legacy System and integrity of Oracle data. Coordinated all credit and re-bill activities for service. Partnered frequently with the sales, collection, finance, and tax team to manage escalation.

- Leading the transition of billing knowledge in short notice within 2 weeks by migrating the task from South Africa team to Kuala Lumpur hub covering MEA region including develop new brand of SOP.
- Responsible for the entire Middle East & African (MEA) billing process, covering 23 countries,
 350 customers and 7,000 invoices per year with revenue GBP 10m per year
- Reconcile billing data and order management data by archiving On Time Delivery (OTD) by
 99% to ensure accuracy, complete invoicing and right first time (RFT).
- Summarize the date of raw use and come out with one project automation by saving up 25% times of 1 FTE and reducing human error whereby credit note was reduced from 3% to 1%.
- Analyze customer data/accounts to identify discrepancies on Telkom Billing and quickly resolve all variances by reducing complaints to meet customer expectations.
- Maintained customer records to ensure accurate, complete billing and external audit, such as purchase order, order form, customer contract and tax certificates.
- Deliver (Responsible BT top 50 customer-MEA) Anglo American for their budgeting and PO raising with 150-200 annual quotes over GBP 4,000,000.
- Accurate and timely raising of the supplier Purchase Order achieved (PO) or invoice for AP process.
- Evaluating data, order form and vendor PO successfully reduces invoice cancellation by 95% during the order management phase

EDUCATION

• 2006 | Bachelor in Degree – Mathematic Computer & Industry | University of

TRAINING/CERTIFICATION

- Prince2 Agile training (Foundation)
- Lean Six Sigma Green Belt (Mar'21 by Intact Prolink-accredited by The Council Six Sigma Certification, USA)
- Soft Skill Management (Internal Training)
- Negotiation Skill Training (Internal Training)
- Developing Personal Resilience (Internal Training)